Azad Mamiyev

Android Developer

Baku, Azerbaijan

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/azadmamiyev/

https://github.com/siftoshka

Profile

An Android Developer with 4 years of experience in developing, designing, and maintaining Android apps in multiple industries such as product tech companies, startups, and consulting agencies. Experienced in delivering features via A/B Testing, building Bitrise pipelines, writing tests, refactoring, and optimizing existing code.

Professional Experience

Software Engineer, Azercell *?*

Sep 2023 - present

• Successfully managed the smooth migration of users to the newly separated application.

Baku, Azerbaijan

• Developing and integrating payment features.

Mobile Platform Developer, Cookpad &

Aug 2022 – Jul 2023

• Migrated a flow of onboarding screens from XML Views to Jetpack Compose.

Bristol, United Kingdom

• Worked on building, editing, and optimizing Bitrise pipelines

- Covered features with unit, integration, and E2E tests.
- Assisted iOS Engineers with migration to use generated paths using CreateAPI.
- Implemented enhancements to the media player, significantly improving the user experience.
- Managed the release process, ensuring timely deployment of updates and monitoring Crashlytics for real-time crash reporting.

Android Developer, ByAllMeans 🤌

Aug 2020 – Jul 2022

Developed chat-related features with reactions.

Prague, Czech Republic

- Actively participated in product management, design & QA team meetings.
- Implemented Google Play Billing Library.
- Maintained the existing project with improvements to user experience.

Education

MSc., Web & Software Engineering, Czech Technical University in Prague

Sep 2019 – Sep 2021

• Experienced in genetic algorithms and management information systems.

Prague, Czech Republic

• Well-versed in patterns, user interface design, and networking.

BSc., Computer Science, Azerbaijan State Oil and Industry University

Sep 2015 – Jun 2019

• Gained experience working on group projects.

Baku, Azerbaijan

Skills

Kotlin, Swift, Java, Coroutines, Jetpack Compose, Kotlin Multiplatform, Networking, Modularisation, MVVM, MVI, Unit and UI Testing, Continuous Integration, Gradle, Figma

Personal Projects

Habitube, Movie Library App 🔗

- Successfully facilitated seamless migration from legacy technologies (Java, RxJava, XML Views) to modern development technologies (Kotlin, Coroutines, Compose) for end users.
- Designed elegant and user-friendly interfaces using Figma.

Languages

English (Fluent) | Azerbaijani (Native) | Russian (Native) | Turkish (Limited) | Czech (Basic)